CYRIL ALVAREZ ADRIAANSEN

Madrid, Spain

BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER | CRYPTOCURRENCY TRADING | SALES

Dynamic, accomplished Trading Professional highly regarded for 13+ years of progressive experience in driving equity and cryptocurrency trading/sales and blockchain efforts. Respected as a motivational, influential leader and collaborator who uses technical expertise to understand markets and trading positions, ensuring profitability. Builds and maintains lasting relationships, driving new revenue through a people-focused approach. Exemplary training qualifications include an intensive Fintech Programme with the University of Oxford. Out-of-the-box thinker committed to making continuous improvements in risk management and trading/market analysis to enable growth.

SELECTED HIGHLIGHTS

- Delivered critical strategic and tactical insights as a member of the Steering Committee at 2Gether.global.
- Managed initiative for the Initial Virtual Financial Asset Offering (IVFAO), and authored a subsequent handbook to convey best practices and common issues during the effort.
- Used data-driven assessments in investing in a wide array of cryptocurrencies, and act as an ICO Advisor.
- Exceeded annual commission quota by 15%, handling equity, bond, and forex trade execution via DMA, algorithms, dark pools, and brokers while collaborating with cross-functional employees at Castle Harbour Securities.
- Drove strict and continuous regulatory compliance, and oversaw financial and technical analysis to determine lucrative trading situations at BTIG Ltd., boosting profits by up to 10% despite volatile market conditions.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Business Development
- Communication
- Client Training

- Cryptocurrency Trading
- Equity Trading
- Trade Positioning
- Market & Trend Analysis
- Sales Director
- Negotiations & Contracts
- Relationship Building
- Javascript Programming

Professional Experience

2GETHER.GLOBAL | MADRID, SPAIN | 2017 - PRESENT

Head of Trading & Blockchain

- Deliver critical strategic and tactical insights as a member of the Steering Committee.
- Demonstrate exceptional technical acumen in creating the Trading & Blockchain architecture.
- Build pre-ICO and ICO Smart contracts in Solidity, ensuring attainment of short- and long-term goals.
- Provide crucial advice across the organization on Fintech & Decentralised Finance (DeFi) to support up to 30% in annual revenue growth, earning a reputation for diligence and blockchain savvy.
- Helmed initiative for the Initial Virtual Financial Asset Offering (IVFAO), and authored a subsequent handbook to convey best practices and common issues during the effort.

MADRID, GENEVA, LONDON | 2013 - PRESENT

Consultant/Crypto Trader

- Incorporate data-driven assessments in investing in a wide array of cryptocurrencies, and act as an ICO Advisor.
- Expand expertise at every opportunity with all aspects of arbitrage and day trading.
- Focus on improving forecasting and trend assessments, learned JavaScript and Python programming language.

CASTLE HARBOUR SECURITIES | LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM | 2011 - 2013

Sales Trader (Managing Director)

- Exceeded annual commission quota by 15%, handling equity, bond, and forex trade execution via DMA, algorithms, dark pools, and brokers while collaborating with cross-functional employees.
- Advised/identified appropriate investments and managed capital exposure as a trusted expert with risk management principles; noted as essential to a 10% upturn in overall company growth.
- Handled extensive market information, research. and news to organize sales efforts and improve trading.
- Achieved optimal trade execution by forging productive, professional relationships with multiple stakeholders, excelling as the primary liaison with technical trading questions.
- Provided client with a wide array of input to improve their portfolio and exceed expectations.
- Stocks monitoring: upgrades/downgrades and corporate actions: dividends, corporate reporting, etc.

BTIG LTD. | LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM | 2009 - 2011

Sales/Execution Trader (Vice President)

- Revised investment history and incorporated technical and fundamental analysis to establish trading positions;
 selected to train new hires on all related sales and trading functions
- Analyzed strategic risk assessment strategies to maximize portfolio performance and minimize downside exposure consistently, building out subsequent standard operating procedures used across the entire organization.
- Drove strict and continuous regulatory compliance, and oversaw financial and technical analysis to determine lucrative trading situations, boosting profits by up to 10% despite volatile market conditions.
- Maintained comprehensives record of clients and fostered continued workflow.
- Provided periodic feedback to clients and gained trust as a dedicated and capable resource.

JABRE CAPITAL PARTNERS SA | GENEVA, SWITZERLAND | 2007 - 2009

Trade Support (Associate)

- Supported 5 portfolio managers with \$4B under management in various funds; performed extensive research on new systems and technologies to improve market assessments and other data-heavy decisions.
- Maintained transactions in a wide array of systems, coordinating with a team of 30.
- Built tailored reports on convertible bonds, equity, options, and more while focusing on positive business impacts.
- Identified efficiency improvements to increase year-over-year profits by 5%.

Additional Experience: Trainee Derivatives Advisor, Bank Pictet & Cie, 2006

EDUCATION

University of Oxford: 2018 – *Fintech Programme*

University of Montreal – Bachelor of Science (Candidate) – Political Science

ADDITIONAL CREDENTIALS

TECHNICAL SKILLS	Linux, GitHub, Google Apps Script, Solidity, JavaScript (MERN), HTML, CSS, Python etc.
Languages	English, French, and Spanish
Professional Development	IronHack, Full-stack JavaScript Development
	Certified Blockchain Developer (CBD)
	Certified Solidity Developer (CSD)
	Certified Smart Contract Developer (CSCD)
	Certified Bitcoin Professional (CBP)
	SII Certificate in Investments
VOLUNTEERISM	United Nations, Commission on Human Rights
Interests	Fintech, Blockchain, Cryptocurrencies, Artificial Intelligence, Formula One, Traveling